if you're looking for a new barbell to
handle your olympic lifting needs you
might want to take a hard look at the
force usa ranger barbell the moderate
knurling is great for high rep exercises
the whip is not out of control so you're
gonna keep solid form while lifting and
the pairing of bronze bushings with two
needle bearings in both of the sleeves
are gonna give you a nice spin for your
workouts
what's up everybody it's jake back in a
steamy barbin garage gym with another
review locked and loaded for y'all today
i have the force usa ranger barbell in
for review y'all know how this goes in
this video i'm going to walk you through
everything this bar has to offer from
the price the features some pros and
cons as well as who should or maybe
should not add this to their home gym
before we get started i have to let you
know we've reviewed a lot of barbells on
barbin.com and if you want to browse our
best list just search barbind best
barbells and you can find out for
yourself which ones we like the best
okay so what do i like about the force
usa ranger barbell well let's talk about
the whip if you don't know what that
means that's essentially the bounce that
occurs in a barbell mid lift so that
whip that bounce it's going to help
create some momentum and it's going to
help you out during say a power clean
now since this barbell the whip's not
out of control you can definitely still
use this for bench pressing if you want
to
you can also still use this for your
power lifting movements because the
sleeves don't spin out of control they
have bronze bushings with two needle
bearings in either sleeve so it's going
to create a nice controlled spin but
like i said it doesn't spin out of
control so kind of makes this an
all-around bar at the same time the
knurling is on the moderate side of
things which it's not going to tear up
your hands which is a really nice touch
as well and i really like how this bar
features a black zinc coating personally
i just think it looks great and who
doesn't want their equipment to look
nice right plus you can light up to 1500
pounds on this barbell so clearly
there's a lot to like right here
[Music]
okay so with that being said there's a
few cons i can see with this barbell
starting with the tensile strength and
if you don't know what that means well
it's essentially how strong a barbell is
so the higher the rating the stronger
the bar the ranger is only listed at 170
000 psi and that's really not that
strong force usa actually offers a bar
it's rated at 235 000 psi so you can see
how much higher you really can get in
terms of that tensile strength rating so
some of you elite level lifters out
there might not want to consider this
bar because of that and it might not
meet your needs and considering that the
tensile strength is not that high it's
kind of expensive there's other barbells
out there that feature the same tinsel
strength rating those are going to be a
little bit cheaper and there's also
barbells out there that have a higher
tensile strength rating and they're
around the same price so that's
something worth remembering as well and
i really like the black zinc it looks
really good
but for somebody like myself you're
working out in a hot garage gym this
probably isn't going to be ideal for you
because you're going to need to clean it
more frequently than you'd probably like
to just to keep it in good shape
okay so let's talk about the money now
and what you can expect to spend on this
barbell so unfortunately as of right
this second the ranger is out of stock
so you're gonna need to be put on the
waiting list but once you are able to
purchase this bar you're gonna be
looking at spending just under 300
and that's including shipping now if you
don't want to spend all that money up
front you can absolutely finance your
purchase through a firm and that's going
to split everything up into monthly
payments of about 20 or so now don't get
me wrong this is a pretty good barbell
to add to your home gym but considering
the tensile strength isn't that high i
gotta say it's a bit expensive with that
being said though you can do just about
anything you want with this bar so as
long as you're not power cleaning an
absurd amount of weight or slamming the
bar into the ground like a crazy person
would i think this could suit you just
fine and when you look at the rest of
the market the ranger actually finds
itself right in the middle in terms of
pricing now there's definitely cheaper
ones out there for you to purchase but
those are probably cheaper for a reason
and there's also more expensive ones out
there but those are also going to be
more expensive for a reason so
this is a pretty good barbell for the
recreational lifter because like i said
you can do just about anything with this
barbell and the tensile strength might
be plenty for you and it might not break
on you at all but if you're really
pumping some iron in the gym this might
not be worth the money and you might
want to spend a little bit extra just to
get a bar that can meet your needs
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
with the ranger barbell so as you can
see it's got a nice black zinc coating
on it i personally love it it looks
great you have a regular zinc finish on
your sleeves right here it's worth
mentioning though that this bar only
comes in 20 kilograms so if you're
looking for a 15 or maybe a 10 kilogram
bar you're not gonna get that here so
sparse 86.6 inches in length the
diameter is 28 millimeters and the
loading sleeves are 16 inches long this
can hold up to 1500 pounds and has a
tensile strength rating of around 170
maybe 175 000 psi
[Music]
let's go into a little bit more now on
the features of this bar the knurling
here is
really on the moderate side of things
it's good for a lot of lifts but you
know for a heavy deadlift or you know
any power lifting movements might not be
good enough for you and since
it is black zinc probably not going to
give you as good of a grip as a
stainless steel bar would
and that's also going to come into
effect in terms of corrosion so
black zinc is not the optimal choice for
somebody like me you're in a humid
garage stainless steel is going to be
your best friend in terms of that
you do have
double knurl markings right here that's
really so the inside marking right here
that's for your power lifts like a bench
press it's gonna help you get that wide
grip and the out one outer one that's
for your olympic lifts like a power
clean that's you know same thing for
your wide grip it's gonna help you get
identical hand placement on both sides
of the bar you don't have a center
knurling on this bar which i personally
like kind of irritates my skin sometimes
but you know i can definitely see why
some people would prefer that in their
bar because you do get more grip from
that center knurling the zinc on these
sleeves or it's a regular zinc finish it
looks pretty good but you're gonna find
that there's bronze bushings and two
needle bearings in both of the sleeves
so they're gonna spin
not out of control and i will say that
some barbells out there from other
companies do spin at a higher rate so
that's something worth mentioning one
thing i really love and it seems to be
this is just the case with these force
usa barbells is that the group pattern
is actually cut deeper than some other
barbells out there so i think you're
gonna have the highest chance possible
of keeping your weights locked into
place but i would definitely still go
get some weight collars just to increase
those chances a little bit more
okay y'all i'm gonna give you a nice up
close and personal walk around of this
barbell here let's start with the fact
you do not have a center knurling on
this barbell i personally like that i
don't really want my skin to get
irritated while i'm working out but i
definitely understand why some people
would prefer a center knurling because
well you get better grip you know say
for your hang cleans power cleans that
bar is going to stick to your chest a
little bit better as well as as you're
going to do a back squat it's going to
stick to your back easier as well the
black zinc coating right here does look
really nice i like it it looks
aesthetically pleasing in our gym right
now
the knurling right here it's on the
moderate side of things it's you know
what's what makes this barbell pretty
versatile
but you know if you're focusing on power
lifts specifically you might not be too
crazy about it because it's not cut very
deep it's not very abrasive so you might
not get that you know ideal grip for
those type of lifts the double knurl
markings right here
really come in handy when you're going
to get set up for any wide grip lift you
might want to do so this inside one
right here that's for you know like a
bench press and this outer one right
here that's for power cleans hang cleans
you know
all that good stuff now as we go further
along down the line you'll see we do
have bronze bushings right here and
inside the sleeves obviously you can't
see that right now there's two needle
bearings in both of them so it's going
to give you a nice spin right here but i
will say it doesn't spin as freely as
some other barbells that i've reviewed
for you all
one really cool thing i like about this
bar though is that the grooved pattern
right here is actually cut deeper than a
lot of the other multi-purpose bars that
i have reviewed for you all so
i think when you go and load your plate
you're gonna have a better chance of
keeping everything you know locked into
place while you're working out which is
really nice touch but if you ever feel
worried about it whatsoever and i've
told you all this before i'm going to
tell you again just for your own safety
and just to you know really keep these
locked into place go get yourself some
weight collars
simply slide it on lock it into place
and i mean that's really not going to go
anywhere and we all like that
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the ranger
barbell well this is a pretty good
option for really any recreational
weight lifter to consider because like i
said you can do just about anything you
want with it and odds are the tensile
strength rating is going to be just fine
for you and it's going to be able to
handle the punishment
that you put it through
anybody looking for a barbell for their
olympic or crossfit style lifts you're
probably gonna like this bar too because
that's really what it's tailored for
if you head over to the force usa
website this is listed as an olympic
barbell but you know because these
sleeves don't spin at a super high rate
you can still
definitely use this for your power lifts
and because you can load up to 1500
pounds here you can use the ranger for
all of your heavy lifts really with no
problem
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase this barbell well
for starters
anybody who wants to have a heavy
emphasis on power lifting might not be
too crazy about this bar yeah you can
still do all those style of lifts but
the knurling here is not very abrasive
and it's not cut very deep so
probably not going to provide that
really good grip that you need and
technically that's going to increase
your chances of the bar slipping out of
your hands a little bit and clearly you
don't want that so i would suggest
looking for a specific power bar just to
handle those lifts and to give you that
good grip i was just talking about
anybody loading up super heavy weight
for their power cleans or any other lift
like that might want to be a little
cautious with this bar yeah you can load
up to 1500 pounds with it but you know
the tensile strength rating is only
around 170 000 psi
so
like i said just be careful and you
might want to go get yourself a bar that
does have a higher tissue strength
rating
the black zinc coating you know i love
it i think it looks really good but if
you're somebody like myself all of your
equipment is in a hot garage gym
it's not going to be ideal for you
because you're going to have to clean it
a little bit more than you would if it
was stainless steel which really that's
going to be your best friend in terms of
fighting off corrosion
in a garage like i am and if you're
somebody looking for a bar that's
smaller than this say either 15 or 10
kilograms you're just gonna have to keep
looking because this bar is only
available in 20 kilograms
[Music]
all right y'all that's all i have for
you today over the force usa ranger
barbell this is a really good option to
consider for the recreational lifter
it's able to handle nearly anything you
throw at it in the gym especially those
olympic and crossfit style lifts because
of the moderate knurling right here it's
not going to tear up your hands and the
pairing of bronze bushings as well as
needle bearings in the sleeves going to
give you a nice controlled spin during
those lifts
however if you are throwing around some
super heavy weight in the gym
you might want to consider yourself
another barbell that does feature a
higher tensile strength rating force usa
actually does offer one that you might
want to go snag and if you're living
somewhere that's really hot and humid
like it is here in nashville or you know
you're in a garage like we are
might not be too crazy about that zinc
coating thanks for watching y'all hope
this video taught you a little bit more
about this barbell kind of just what to
expect with it as always stay on the
lookout for my next review but for now
you should definitely head over to
barbin.com to read more about this
barbell just search barbind force usa
ranger barbell review and our article is
going to pull right up for you i'll see
you all next time
[Music]